[

  {
    "question": "Annotation starts with _______ symbol.",
    "answer": "@"
  },
  {
    "question": "Annotation is used for autowiring in Spring _________.",
    "answer": "@Autowired"
  },
  {
    "question": "A web application can be accessed using ___________.",
    "answer": "Browser / URL"
  },
  {
    "question": "Deploy the application ________ So all client can access the application.",
    "answer": "on Server"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the parent annotation for all stereotype annotations in Spring_________.",
    "answer": "@Component"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Annotation Declare a class as a Java-based config class____________.",
    "answer": "@Configuration"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the annotation used to specify the custom properties file location___________.",
    "answer": "@PropertySource"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the Annotation used to inject the properties file data into variable __________.",
    "answer": "@Value"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which annotation allows Spring beans to evaluate SpEL expressions ___________.",
    "answer": "@Value"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the default bean scope in Spring___________.",
    "answer": "singleton"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which scope creates a new bean instance every time it is requested__________.",
    "answer": "prototype"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which annotation is used to execute cleanup logic before a bean is destroyed __________.",
    "answer": "@PreDestroy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which annotation is used to declare bean scope explicitly _______________.",
    "answer": "@Scope"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which annotation is used to execute logic after bean creation and dependency injection_________.",
    "answer": "@PostConstruct"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the default port number of tomcat _________.",
    "answer": "8080"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the annotation used to inject a dependency by name___________.",
    "answer": "@Qualifier"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the syntax used in SpEL #{} or ${} ________.",
    "answer": "#{}"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the syntax used to read properties from a properties file #{} or ${} ________.",
    "answer": "${}"
  },
  {
    "question": "Data flow  Client → __________ → __________ → __________ → Database",
    "answer": "Controller → Service → Repository"
  },
  {
    "question": "Data flow  Database → __________ → __________ → __________ → Client",
    "answer": "Repository → Service → Controller"
  }
]
